Dan Bernier

Back End Developer at TED Conferences

danbernier@gmail.com

Summary

My career started on the second Monday after Y2K (my new employers wanted a week to sort everything out). I've done Java, .Net, and Ruby on Rails. I've worked in the enterprise, mid-size companies, and start-ups. I've worked under gated waterfall, Scrum, Lean, and anarchy methodologies. I've used Windows, Linux, and Macs.

I'm a regular open-source contributor: https://github.com/danbernier. I created WordCram (http://wordcram.org), an open-source Processing library for making word clouds.

I like learning new programming languages. I've been using Ruby since 2005, serious JavaScript since 2007, and playing with Scheme on-and-off since 2007. I've checked out Clojure, Scala, Io, and Self, and written bits of interpreters a half-dozen times.

A healthy local developer community is important to me, so I co-organize http://newhavenrb.org and http://newhaven.io, scheduling meetups, and sometimes presenting. I co-founded and ran the Hartford Ruby Brigade for just over a year.

I write on-line at http://invisibleblocks.com, about software design and programming. I've found I enjoy teaching people about software and math, and the blog serves as an outlet for that.

Specialties: Ruby, JavaScript, Processing.org, Java, Web application development, .Net, C#

Experience

Back End Developer at TED Conferences

January 2017 - Present

developer

August 2010 - Present

I started WordCram, an open-source Processing library for generating word clouds, and released version 0.1 in August 2010. I blog about the project at http://wordcram.org, and tweet at @wordcram.

Senior Software Engineer at Continuity

November 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 2 months)

At Continuity, I was lucky enough to help lead an incredible team of engineers. I spent a decent part of my week coding, but I also mentored and advised developers, and planned for architecture changes so that Continuity could do more, and run more smoothly.

The work was challenging and satisfying on its own; being of service to community banks and credit unions made it especially rewarding. I'm proud of the work we did.

Ruby Developer at SeeClickFix

September 2011 - November 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Maintained Ruby on Rails site seeclickfix.com. Improved test coverage, maintainability, and performance, and reduced technical debt and cost to make changes.

Designed and built a dashboard and CRM for cities to respond to SeeClickFix issues in their municipality, and a knowledge base for cities to answer questions from the social Q&A forum.

Designed and built the Mobile Buttons addon product, so cities can add new buttons to the SeeClickFix iPhone and Android apps immediately, without upgrading.

Created data visualizations of issues from Hurricanes Irene and Sandy and the Boston Marathon bombing.

Senior Application Developer at Evolution Benefits/Evolution1

March 2008 - August 2011 (3 years 6 months)

C# and .Net development on benefits card processing software, in a Scrum-agile environment. I was responsible for code quality, helping with architecture, and mentoring other developers.

Besides normal application development, I often found myself mining C# with Ruby and GraphViz, to help the team understand the architecture, application rights, and build scripts.

Developer at Software Impressions

May 2006 - March 2008 (1 year 11 months)

Software consulting firm, with a focus on an ethics-compliance case management application for Fortune 500 companies. The team is .Net-based, highly technical, flexible, and growing.

Developer at The Hartford

February 2002 - May 2006 (4 years 4 months)

Application design and development for Agent's Portal to The Hartford. Using J2EE with various open source or home-grown libraries and frameworks.

Developer at ING Financial Group

January 2001 - December 2001 (1 year)

Application design and development, and website maintenance. Continuation of previous Aetna Financial Services position, after the buy-out.

Developer at Aetna Financial Services

January 2000 - December 2000 (1 year)

Webmaster, plus some application development.

Education

Central Connecticut State University

BS, Computer Science, 1997 - 2006

Ruby Mendicant University

2011 - 2011

Dan Bernier

Back End Developer at TED Conferences

danbernier@gmail.com



Contact Dan on LinkedIn